Guide to the Virginia Spencer Carr Papers, 1867-2009 RL.00193
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Virginia Spencer Carr papers
1867-2009 and undated, bulk 1970-1977
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Carr, Virginia Spencer
RL.00193
6.6 Linear Feet
Scholar and a professor of American literature at Georgia State University. Her first book was The Lonely Hunter: A Biography of Carson McCullers. Correspondence, notes, drafts, clippings, and other materials used by Carr in writing The Lonely Hunter (1975), a biography of Southern author Carson McCullers. Includes correspondence between Carr and McCullers' friends and relatives and literary and artistic figures, notes from interviews, McCullers family correspondence, genealogy, and drafts of Carr's doctoral dissertation on McCullers as well as drafts and foundry proofs for The Lonely Hunter. Includes material on Yaddo, Saratoga Springs, N.Y., February House, Brooklyn Heights, N.Y., and Bread Loaf Writers' Conference, Middlebury, Vt. Persons represented in the collection include Elizabeth Ames, W. H. Auden, Leonard Bernstein, Paul Bowles, John Ciardi, David Leo Diamond, Granville Hicks, John Huston, Jordan Massee, Louis Untermeyer, Eudora Welty, Tennessee Williams, Leo Lerman, and Eleanor Clarke Warren.
2480 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Virginia Spencer Carr Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1977 and 1981.
Biographical Note
Virginia Spencer Carr earned her Ph.D. at Florida State University in 1969. She taught courses in the American novel, American writers and poets, literature of the South, and the writing of biography at Georgia State University. The Lonely Hunter: A Biography of Carson McCullers was her first book, and was awarded the Francis Butler Simkins Prize from the Southern Historical Society and Longwood College for distinguished writing in Southern History. Her second book, Dos Passos: A Life, was selected Best Book of Nonfiction for 1984 by the Dixie Council of Author and Journalists. Dr. Carr holds an honorary doctorate in humane letters (Lynchburg College). She also was a Senior Fulbright Professor at the University of Wroclaw, Poland (1980), and held the 1993 Stanley J. Kahrl Fellowship in Theater History at Harvard University.
Collection Overview
The Virginia Spencer Carr Papers span the years 1867 to 2009 and document the research and production of Carr's biography of Carson McCullers, The Lonely Hunter. Formats include correspondence, notes, drafts, and clippings. The collection consists of four series: Alphabetical Files, Research Files, Correspondence by McCullers Family, and Drafts and Proofs. The Alphabetical Files Series consists primarily of correspondence and interview notes between Carr and the many individuals she contacted while doing research for her book. Prominent correspondents include David Leo Diamond, Jordan Massee, Edwin Peacock, Mary Mercer, Mary S. Tucker, and Doubleday Publishing. Materials in the Research Files Series also include a large number of copies of correspondence, primarily letters written by Carson McCullers. There are also some clippings, notes from interviews that Carr conducted and letters she received in reaction to the publication of her book. The Correspondence by McCullers Family Series consists of copies of letters written primarily by Carson McCullers to her friends and family, including Reeves McCullers, David Leo Diamond, and her mother, Marguerite Waters Smith. There is also a series of letters McCullers wrote John Huston in the last year of her life. Finally, the Drafts and Proofs Series includes a copy of Carr's doctoral dissertation on Carson McCullers and notes that served in its preparation. There are also edited sections of the manuscript of the The Lonely Hunter, as well as a foundry proof and a galley of the same.
Related Material
Related materials include the Carson McCullers Papers, the Mary E. Mercer Collection of Carson McCullers-Mary Tucker Correspondence, the Edwin Peacock Papers, and the Mary Sames Tucker Papers, all housed at Duke University in the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
American literature -- Women authors; Women authors, American -- Southern States; Yaddo (Saratoga Springs, N.Y.); February House (Brooklyn Heights, N.Y.); Huston, John, 1906-1987; Lerman, Leo; McCullers, Carson, 1917-1967; Warren, Eleanor, 1913-; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990; Ames, Elizabeth; Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Bread Loaf Writers' Conference at Middlebury College; Carr, Virginia Spencer. Lonely hunter; Ciardi, John, 1916-1986; Diamond, David, 1915-2005; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982
- Alphabetical Files Series, 1867-2009 and undated, 7 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The largest in the collection, this series consists primarily of correspondence and interview notes with various people to whom Carr wrote while doing research for her biography of McCullers. Among the many writers, artists, and friends of McCullers that Carr contacted, there are Edward Albee, W.H. Auden, Djuna Barnes, Simone de Beauvoir, Elizabeth Bowen, Salvator Dali, Greta Garbo, Graham Greene, Christopher Isherwood, and Alberto Moravia. While many of the people Carr addressed refused to cooperate with her biography, numerous others offered their assistance, and the series includes significant material from and about David Diamond, Jordan Massee, Edwin Peacock, Mary S. Tucker, and Tennessee Williams. The series is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the correspondent, but is preceded by four folders with general information, including addresses and notes about the people represented in the series.
  - Addresses, 1970-1971 and undated (Box 1)
  - Bibliography, undated (Box 1)
  - Information folder, 1977 and undated (Box 1)
  - Notes on persons in files, undated (Box 1)
  - Abels, Cirilly, 1972-1973 and undated (Box 1)
  - Adams, John Vincent, 1946-1975 and undated (Box 1)
  - Albee, Edward Franklin, 1963-1975 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Aimee, 1968-1974 and undated (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1952-1973 and undated (Box 1)
  - Ames, Elizabeth, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - Arkin, Alan, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Arvin, Newton, 1971 and undated (Box 1)
  - Aschaffenburg, Walter, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Aswell, Mary Louis (White), 1972 (Box 1)
  - Auchincloss, Louis, 1971-1976 and undated (Box 1)
  - Auden, W. H., 1970-1975 and undated (Box 1)
  - Avedon, Richard, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Awards of McCullers, 1970-1971 and undated (Box 1)
  - Bahr, Jerome, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Balakian, Nona, 1961-1973 and undated (Box 1)
  - Bancou, Mariello, 1971-1974 and undated (Box 1)
  - Barnes, Djuna, 1965-1973 (Box 1)
  - Baxter, Anne, 1971-1975 and undated (Box 1)
  - Bay, Andre and Chedid, Andree, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Beaton, Cecil, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
  - de Beauvoir, Simone, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Berman, Eugene, 1965-1971 (Box 1)
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1968-1970 and undated (Box 1)
  - Bigelow, Paul, 1971-1974 (Box 1)
  - Blackwell, Betsy Talbot, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Bloomgarden, Kermit, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Bolster, George, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Bourjaily, Vance, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Bowen, Elizabeth, 1951-1972 and undated (Box 1)
  - Bowles, Paul, 1970-1971 and undated (Box 1)
  - Boyle, Kay, 1962-1971 (Box 1)
  - Bradley Library, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Bread Loaf Writers Conference, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 1)
  - Britten, Benjamin, 1968-1970 and undated (Box 1)
  - Brown, John Lackey, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 2)
  - Burford, Kay, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Burnett, Whit, 1936-1975 and undated (Box 2)
  - Calisher, Hortense, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 2)
  - Cameron, Polly, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1973-1976 and undated (Box 2)
  - Charleston Evening Post, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Cheney, Brainard, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Cheltenham Arts Festival, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Clark-Schwarzenbach, Annemarle, 1940-1973 and undated (Box 2)
  - Clarke, David, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Clay, Helena, 1972 and undated (Box 2)
  - Cleckley, Hervey Milton, 1970-1975 (Box 2)
  - Clurman, Harold, 1950-1973 (Box 2)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Columbus College Foundation Grant, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Connelly, Mark, 1971 and undated (Box 2)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Cordona, Charlie, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Cornell, Katherine, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1963-1975 (Box 2)
  - Crawford, Cheryl, 1968-1973 (Box 2)
  - Dahl-Wolfe, Louise, 1971-1973 and undated (Box 2)
  - Dale, Marion, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Dalmas, John, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Dali, Salvador, 1961-1972 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Dorothy Salisbury, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Deceased, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - del Corso, Gasparo, 1972-1973 and undated (Box 2)
  - Deutsch, Babette, 1973 (Box 2)
  - de Wilde, Brandon, 1961-1972 (Box 2)
  - Diamond, David, 1966-1975 and undated (Box 2)
  - Dinesen, Isak, 1957-1974 and undated (Box 2)
  - Doar, Harriet, 1963-1973 (Box 2)
  - Doubleday Publishing, 1971-1976 and undated (folders 1-2 of 3) (Box 2)
  - Doubleday Publishing, 1971-1976 and undated (folder 3 of 3) (Box 3)
  - Drutman, Irving, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Edel, Leon, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Erlich, Leonard, 1972-1974 and undated (Box 3)
  - Eisendrath, David, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Ellison, Ralph Waldo, 1971 (Box 3)
  - English, Margaret, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Erskine, Albert, 1972-1974 (Box 3)
  - Eustis, Helen, 1972-1974 and undated (Box 3)
  - Evans, Oliver, 1952-1970 and undated (Box 3)
  - February House, 1867-1972 and undated (Box 3)
  - Feibleman, Peter, 1971-1974 and undated (Box 3)
  - Ferguson, Nancy, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Fite, Harvey, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Flanner, Janet, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 3)
  - Foley, Martha, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Publishers, 1972-1974 and undated (Box 3)
  - Formentor Prize, 1962 (Box 3)
  - French, Kenneth, 1970-1975 (Box 3)
  - Fullilove, Jack, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Garbo, Greta, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Garnett, David, 1963-1973 (Box 3)
  - Gascoyne, David, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Gikow, Rita, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Gordon, Larry, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Goyen, William, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Graphic House, Inc., 1974 (Box 3)
  - Grau, Shirley Ann, 1959-1975 (Box 3)
  - Greene, Graham, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Hackett, Albert and Frances, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Hammerschlag, Ernst, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Harris, Julie, 1970-1972 and undated (Box 3)
  - Harvey, Helen, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Hassan, Ihab, 1964-1975 (Box 3)
  - Havoc, Julie, 1966-1973 (Box 3)
  - Hayes, Helen, 1966-1973 and undated (Box 3)
  - Heffelfinger, Heaton, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Heller, Joseph, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Hicks, Granville, 1964-1973 and undated (Box 3)
  - Holton, Nina, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Houghton Miflin Publishing, undated (Box 3)
  - Howard, Elizabeth Jane, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Howard, Leila Caetani, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Howe, Irving, 1961-1971 (Box 3)
  - Hull, Helen Rose, 1964-1970 (Box 3)
  - Huston, John, 1966-1976 (Box 3)
  - Isherwood, Christopher, 1968-1973 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Greer, 1947-1973 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Nunnally, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Uwe, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Kaldor, Peter, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Kallman, Chester, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Kantorowicz, Alfred, 1970-1976 (Box 4)
  - Kazin, Alfred, 1971-1975 (Box 4)
  - Keathley, George, 1966-1971 (Box 4)
  - Kellogg, Marjorie, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1968-1973 (Box 4)
  - Kramer, Stanley, 1968-1973 (Box 4)
  - Kuhn, Werner, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Lang, George, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Lantz, Robert, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
  - Lasky, Floria, 1970-1976 and undated (Box 4)
  - Lee, Gypsy Rose, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Lee, Harper, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Leggett, John, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Lehmann, John, 1973 and undated (Box 4)
  - Lehmann, Rosa, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - Lenya, Lotte, 1966-1976 and undated (Box 4)
  - Lerman, Leo, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Stanley, 1970-1975 and undated (Box 4)
  - Library Correspondence, 1971-1974 and undated (Box 4)
  - Linscott, Robert, 1965-1973 (Box 4)
  - Logan, Joshua, 1973 and undated (Box 4)
  - Lonely Hunting, undated (Box 4)
  - Long, Margaret, 1965-1972 (Box 4)
  - Lopatnikoff, Nikolai, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Luce, Claire Booth, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Lyndon, Andrew, 1970-1975 and undated (Box 4)
  - Maas, Willard and Marie, 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - McCullers's Memorabilia, 1940-1973 and undated (Box 4)
  - McCullers's Poetry, 1941-1970 (Box 4)
  - McCullers Symposium, 1970-1975 (Box 4)
  - McDowell, David, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - McGill, Ralph, 1971 and undated (Box 4)
  - MacGregor, Robert M., 1972 (Box 4)
  - Mclendon, Gay Noe, 1972-1974 (Box 4)
  - Mac Neice, Louis, 1942-1970 (Box 4)
  - Macombe, Rev. Anthony, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Magazines, 1971-1972 and undated (Box 4)
  - Magruder, Felicia, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Malin, Irving, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Mangione, Jerre, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Mann, Golo, 1942-1972 and undated (Box 4)
  - Mann, Marty, 1972-1973 and undated (Box 4)
  - Mann, Theodore, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Marks, Joseph, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Marks, Robert, 1970-1973 (Box 5)
  - Marre, Albert, 1973 and undated (Box 5)
  - Martin, Mary, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - Martineau, Florence, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Massee, Jordan, 1951-1976 and undated (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - McCullers, James Reeves Jr., 1967-1973 and undated (Box 5)
  - Medical records, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 5)
  - Mercer, Mary, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 5)
  - Miller, Arthur, 1970-1973 (Box 5)
  - Mielziner, Jo, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1974 and undated (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 5)
  - Mohrt, Michael, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - Monti, Mario, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Moody, Rev. Howard, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Moravia, Alberto, 1970-1973 (Box 5)
  - Morris, Alice, 1970-1973 (Box 5)
  - Morris, Ira and Edita, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Morrison, Theodore, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Mortgaged Heart, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Mullin, Josephine, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Murray, Natalie Denesi, 1971-1973 (Box 5)
  - Murray, Terry, 1970 (Box 5)
  - New York Times, 1940-1971 (Box 6)
  - Newhouse, Edward, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 6)
  - Nin, Anaïs, 1969-1970 and undated (Box 6)
  - Nobel Committee of the Swedish Academy, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Orkin, Ruth, 1971-1974 and undated (Box 6)
  - Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Page, Lucy Q., 1972 (Box 6)
  - Peacock, Edwin, 1970-1975 and undated (Box 6)
  - Pears, Peter, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
  - Permission lists, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Phelps, Robert, 1968-1971 (Box 6)
  - Photographers, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Pitts, Rebecca E., 1972-1974 and undated (Box 6)
  - Plagemann, Bentz, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Polakov, Lester, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Poor, Henry Varnum, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Porter, Dr. Frederick S., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1970-1976 (Box 6)
  - Presley, Dr. Delma E., 1970-1972 and undated (Box 6)
  - Price, Edward, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Pritchett, Victor Sawdon, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Pugh, St. Clair, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Quintero, Jose, 1972-1974 and undated (Box 6)
  - Rahv, Philip, 1972-1974 (Box 6)
  - Redbook, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Reed, Rex, 1968-1972 (Box 6)
  - Reeder, Ida, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 6)
  - Rodgers, Mary, 1970-1975 and undated (Box 6)
  - Rodriguez, Pancho, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
  - Romano, Emanuel, 1961-1972 and undated (Box 6)
  - Rougemont, Denis de, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1962-1974 and undated (Box 6)
  - Rutherford, Dame Margaret, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Ryan, Thomas C., 1970-1973 and undated (Box 6)
  - Sagan, Franqoise, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Saint George's Hospital (London, England), 1973 (Box 6)
  - Saint Just, Maria, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Saint Subber, Arnold, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1972 (Box 6)
  - School Records (Carson Smith McCullers), 1930-1972 (Box 6)
  - Schorer, Mark, 1963-1975 (Box 6)
  - Searle, Ronald, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Sibley, Celestine, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Sitwell, Dame Edith and Sir Sacheverell, 1954-1976 and undated (Box 6)
  - Simmons, Dawn Pepita (Langley-Hall), 1954-1974 and undated (Box 6)
  - Smith, Lamar, 1970-1974 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Lillian, 1965-1972 and undated (Box 6)
  - Smith, Margarita G., 1970-1972 and undated (Box 6)
  - Smith, Oliver, 1961-1973 and undated (Box 6)
  - Smith, Simeon, 1970 and undated (Box 7)
  - Snelling, Paula, 1936-1971 (Box 7)
  - Spender, Stephen, 1965-1972 (Box 7)
  - Stafford, Jean, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Stapleton, Maureen, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Starke Avenue, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Steele, Max, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Stern, James, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - Strassburg, Lee and Paula, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Stringer, Edward, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Styron, William, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Sykes, Gerald, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Taylor, Elizabeth, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1966-1970 (Box 7)
  - Trussell, Dr. Ray E., 1973 (Box 7)
  - Tucker, Mary, 1970-1973 (Box 7)
  - University of Texas (Austin) Library, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 7)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1941-1975 and undated (Box 7)
  - Valente, Alfredo, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Van den Heuvel, Jean, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 7)
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1971-1974 (Box 7)
  - Vidal, Gore, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Von Opel, Margo, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Walden, Robert, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 7)
  - Walter, Eugene, 1965-1973 (Box 7)
  - Warren, Eleanor (Clark) and Robert Penn, 1955-1973 and undated (Box 7)
  - Waters, Ethel, 1950-1971 (Box 7)
  - Watkins, Armitage, 1971-1972 and undated (Box 7)
  - Webb, Constance, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 7)
  - Wells, Ruth, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Welty, Eudora, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Wersba, Barbara, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1965-1972 and undated (Box 7)
  - Whitehead, Robert, 1949-1974 (Box 7)
  - Will (Carson Smith McCullers), 1951-1970 (Box 7)
  - William Morris Theatrical Agency, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
  - Williams, Tennessee, 1948-1976 and undated (Box 7)
  - Wood, Audrey, 1970-1973 (Box 7)
  - Woolfolk, Harrell, 1971-1975 (Box 7)
  - Woodruff, Kathleen, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Wouk, Herman, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Yaddo School for Writers, 1971-1975 (Box 7)
  - Young, Marguerite, 1970-1973 (Box 7)
  - Yourcenar, Marguerite, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Zeigler, John, 1989-2009 (Box 7)
  - Zinnemann, Fred, 1973 (Box 7)
- Research Files Series, 1907-1976 and undated, 2 boxes
  Consists of various materials that Carr compiled while preparing the publication of her biography of McCullers. The bulk are copies of correspondence (written primarily by Carson McCullers), notes from interviews Carr conducted, clippings, and several journal articles. Other documents in the series include acknowledgements for The Lonely Hunter and readers' reactions to the book's publication. The series is arranged alphabetically, and then chronologically within individual folders.
  - Acknowledgments for book, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 8)
  - Chronology (of Carson Smith McCullers), undated (Box 8)
  - Genealogy, undated (Box 8)
  - Genealogy, 1907-1972 and undated (Box 8)
  - Hometown interview notes, 1970-1971 and undated (Box 8)
  - Interpolated interview notes, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Letters relating to The Lonely Hunter
    - 1972-1976 Feb. (Box 8)
    - 1975 (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - 1976 Mar.-Dec. and undated (Box 8)
  - Local people, 1970-1973 and undated (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 8)
  - Pictures and photographers (comments), 1963-1974 and undated (Box 8)
  - Sources, 1933-1943 (folders 1-2 of 11) (Box 8)
  - Sources, 1944-1975 (folders 3-11 of 11) (Box 9)
- Correspondence by McCullers Family Series, 1933-1967 and undated, 2 boxes
  Contains correspondence written primarily by Carson McCullers, even though there are several by others, including her husband Reeves. By far the greatest number of letters are from McCullers to David Leo Diamond, written in the early and middle 1940s, and to John Huston, from the last year of her life (1966-1967). The series also contains some correspondence addressed to Jordan Massee, Edwin Peacock, Muriel Rukeyser, and Carson's mother, Marguerite Smith. Folders are arranged in alphabetical order; materials inside them are organized chronologically.
  - Arvin, Newton, 1941 (Box 9)
  - Bradley Library, 1958 (Box 9)
  - Burnett, Whit, 1936 (Box 9)
  - Connelly, Mare, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Diamond, David, 1941-1961 and undated (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Harris, Julie, 1955 (Box 10)
  - Huston, John, 1966-1967 and undated (Box 10)
  - Kantorowiez, Alfred, undated (Box 10)
  - Mann, Klaus, 1942-1945 (Box 10)
  - Massee, Jordan, 1949 (Box 10)
  - McCullers, James Reeves, 1933-1951 and undated (Box 10)
  - Peacock, Edwin, 1943-1963 and undated (Box 10)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1941-1942 (Box 10)
  - Smith, Lillian, 1954-1961 (Box 10)
  - Smith, Marguerite (Waters), 1942-1951 (Box 10)
  - Strassburg, Lee and Paula, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Walden, Robert and Newberry, Edward, 1954 (Box 10)
  - Whitehead, Robert, 1949 (Box 10)
  - Woodruff, Kathleen, undated (Box 10)
- Drafts and Proofs Series, 1975 and undated, 2 boxes
  Divided into three subseries, the first of which contains a copy of Virginia Carr's doctoral dissertation on Carson McCullers, completed in 1969 at Florida State University, and the notes for her dissertation. The second subseries consists of manuscript portions of the The Lonely Hunter, edited with marginalia by such persons as David Leo Diamond, Leo Lerman, and Eleanor Warren. Finally, in the last subseries, there is a foundry proof and a galley of the completed biography. Folders in the series are arranged alphabetically; materials in them remain in original order.
  - Doctoral dissertation (Box 10)
    - Chapters 1-End, undated (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Notes, undated (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - Edited manuscripts
    - Abels, Cyrilly, undated (Box 10)
    - Bancou, Marielle, undated (Box 10)
    - Calisher, Hortense, undated (Box 10)
    - Diamond, David, undated (Box 10)
  - Edited manuscripts (Box 11)
    - Eustis, Helen, undated (Box 11)
    - Hellman, Lillian, undated (Box 11)
    - Lerman, Leo, undated (Box 11)
    - Newhouse, Edward, undated (Box 11)
    - Plagemann, Bentz, undated (Box 11)
    - Warren, Eleanor (Clark), undated (Box 11)
  - Foundry proof, The Lonely Hunter, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Galley, The Lonely Hunter, 1975 (Box 11)